A Guide to the Jeffrey Miller Papers Used in Preparing His Bibliography of Paul Bowles, 1942 (1960-1972) 1972
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Jeffrey Miller Papers Used in Preparing His Bibliography of Paul Bowles, 1942 (1960-1972) 1972
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9917
This collection consists of 700 items, 3 sound tape reels and 28 sound discs.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased from Gotham Book Mart and Gallery, Inc., through the Rare Book Department, University of Virginia Library on 1973 November 20.
Scope and Content Information
Bowles material in the collection includes photocopies of arrangements of American folksongs, an interview with Dan Halpern, the manuscript and page proofs of Without Stopping, and correspondence with Ira Cohen, Lawrence Ferlinghetti and Miller. Miller's correspondence about the bibliography constitutes the bulk of the collection which also contains reviews by Bowles, tapes of his readings, records of his musical compositions, and photographs.
Contents List
- American Folksongs arranged for Piano Solo for New York City Music Project, W.P.A. Art Program. n.d., TMs (photocopy) (Box 1)
- American Folksongs arranged for Voice and Piano for New York City W.P.A. Music Project. n.d., TMs (photocopy) (Box 1)
- Interview with Paul Bowles by Dan Halpern 1970 Spring, TMs (photocopy) (Box 1)
- Interview with Paul Bowles by Dan Halpern, revised 1970 Spring, TMs (photocopy) (Box 1)
- "Post Colonial Interlude in Tangier" n.d., TMs (photocopy) (Box 1)
- Twelve American Folksongs arranged for Voice and piano n.d., TMs (photocopy) (Box 1)
- Up Above the World n.d., AMs (fragment) (Box 1)
- Without Stopping Paul Bowles Autobiography n.d., TMs (photocopy) (Box 1)
- Without Stopping n.d., Page Proof (copy) (Box 1)
- Letters
  - Paul Bowles to Ira Cohen 1963 September 9-1970 June 25 & n.d., 48 TLS (photocopies) (Box 1)
  - Paul Bowles to Lawrence Ferlinghetti 1961 December 12-1970 May 11, 35 TLS (photocopies) (Box 1)
  - Paul Bowles to Catherine Hartman 1970 September 11, TLS (Box 1)
  - Paul Bowles to M.F. Legras 1967 December 26, TLS (Box 1)
  - Paul Bowles to John Lehman 1949 August 25-1951 October 6, 5 ALS/TLS (Box 1)
  - Paul Bowles to Jeffrey Miller 1969 November 9-1972 March 23, 14 TLS (in part carbon copies) (Box 1)
  - Paul Bowles to Barbara Turner 1960 November 20-1961 June 11, 3 TLS/TPCS (Box 1)
  - Correspondence of Jeffrey Miller with publishers of his bibliography of Paul Bowles, A-Q 1969-1972, ca. 300 items (Box 2)
  - Correspondence of Jeffrey Miller with publishers of his bibliography of Paul Bowles, R-Z 1969-1972, ca. 100 items (Box 3)
- Photographs
  - Paul Bowles in the Land of the Jumblies 1968 September 17, 3 strip pos movie stills 16mm (Box 3)
  - Paul Bowles in the Land of the Jumblies 1968 September 17, Print (Box 3)
  - Paul Bowles with [Lawrence Ferlinghetti?] 1968 September 17, Print (Box 3)
  - Paul Bowles at a cocktail party 1968September, Print (Box 3)
  - Paul Bowles at a cocktail party 1968 September 17, Print (Box 3)
  - Paul Bowles at a cocktail party 1968 September 17, Print (Box 3)
  - Paul Bowles at a cocktail party 1968 September 17, Print (Box 3)
  - Paul Bowles at a cocktail party 1968 September 17, Print (Box 3)
  - Paul Bowles at a cocktail party 1968 September 17, Print (Box 3)
  - Paul Bowles at Villa Mouneria, Tangier, Morocco with others. n.d., Print (Box 3)
- Miscellaneous
  - Invitations, including a private reception, reading and private film screenings in honor of Bowles 1968 September 17 and [1968] December 10, ca. 7 items (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous envelopes 1970-1972, ca. 26 items (Box 3)
  - Newspaper clippings including critical articles written by Bowles for the New York Herald Tribune. 1942-1972, ca. 56 items (Box 3)
  - Notes including those of Jeffrey Miller to himself and to his wife n.d., Ca. 6 items (Box 3)
  - Printed material including book reviews, magazine articles and theater programs. 1958-1971, ca. 18 items (Box 3)
  - Receipts from a certified letter, Miller to William Targ 1971 June 9, Ca. 2 items (Box 3)
- Phonodisc Recordings
  - Concerto re Two Pianos, Winds and Percussion by Paul Bowles, Columbia Records Inc. 1950, 1 record
  - "A Picnic Cantata" and "Sonata for Two Pianos" by Paul Bowles, Columbia n.d., 1 record
  - Jilala, Trance Records [An Islamic Ritual] n.d., 1 record
  - Modern Waltzes for Two Pianos, including "Night Waltz" by Bowels, Columbia 1950, 1 record
  - "Music for a Farce" and Sc讥s d' Anabasa" by Bowles, Columbia n.d., 1 record
  - Musical score for Tennesse William's Summer and Smoke, Major Records n.d., 5 records
  - Musical score for Tennesse William's The Glass Menagerie, Major Records n.d., 3 records
  - Musical scores for Summer and Smoke, The Glass Menagerie, and My Heart's in the Highland, Major Records n.d., 4 records
  - Night without Sleep and Other Songs, music composed by Bowles, lyrics by Charles Henri Ford, Disc Co. Of America n.d., 3 records
  - Sonata for Two Pianos composed by Bowles, played by Arthur Gold and Robert Fizdale, Concert Hall Limited Editions 1946, 2 records
  - Songs by American Composers including "Blue Mountain Ballads" composed by Bowles, lyrics by Tennessee Williams, Desto Recordings n.d., 2 records
  - The Wind Remains including "The Wind Remains," "Music for a Farce" and "Letters from Morocco" by Paul Bowles, MGM Records n.d., 1 record
  - Paul Bowles reads The Delicate Prey and A Distant Episode, Spoken Arts Inc. n.d., 1 record
  - Reading of The Glass Menagerie by Tennessee Williams, The Theatre Recording Society, Caedmon Productions. 1964, 2 records
- Tape Recordings
  - Reading of "In the Land of the Jumblies" by Bowles. n.d., 2 reels
  - Reading of "Me of the Assembly" by Bowles 1968 September 17, 1 reel